https://github.com/eKioga

erickpost@gmail.com

Eric K. Post -----

https://portfolio.ekpost.net

Summary

Service Desk Expert and System Administrator: Onboarding to offboarding and everything in between. Skilled in troubleshooting, analytics, end-user training, solutions engineering and deployments. I have a decade of experience in the support and administration of Windows environments along with various internal and cloud based applications and services.

Key Projects

- Reduced technical debt and tickets by largely automating critical Help Desk functions. This includes: user creation, asset management and PC imaging along with all software reporting, deployment and patching. Built alert and reporting systems for the monitoring of both network and node health.
- Saved company time and money while reducing potential technical debt by reorganizing internal IT access rights and enacting the Principles of Least Privilege (PoLP) for all employees of the IT department. After thorough planning and receiving approval, I audited and configured our Domain Controller to match the agreed security and access rights specifications for services like Active Directory and DNS. Rewrote internal IT documentation and procedures with low skilled employees in mind. This allowed entry level IT staff the ability to safely administer user accounts and applications without RDP or Windows Server knowledge.
- Lead engineer for the Google Apps to Office 365 migration project that included constant communication with company VPs, outside vendors, and Microsoft consultants. I tested feasibility relative to the current environment, researched and implement solutions to achieve the project goals. The project itself was successfully completed despite being short-staffed due to my solutions engineering, rigorous testing, skills with automation, user communication along with continuous collaboration with my team and outside resources.
- Lead engineer on the Symantec to Trend Micro Worry-Free Business firewall migration along with its deployment to servers and 300+ end user machines. I was also the main administrator and collaborated with the IT Director in order to create the necessary configurations to manage the firewall's behavior, URL filtering and policy management.
- Project lead to outfit all our satellite offices nationwide with WiFi options including an internal corporate connection, a quest connection and an employee outside connection. I collaborated with vendors in the planning and configuration of the back-end stack (Panorama, Aruba, Clearpass). I handled the user facing side of the project entirely myself. This included rigorous testing, all the user communications (announcements, how-to guides, gathering feedback), creating the GPOs, packaging and automating the deployment of the supplemental software.

Technology Proficiencies

- Process Flows, Call-Tracking Tools, Ticketing systems: HEAT, ZenDesk, Snipe-IT.
- Software: MS Office, anti-virus, Citrix receiver, Cisco AnyConnect, Junos Pulse, Skype.
- Cloud Services: Office 365, Google Apps, Trend Micro Worry-Free Business.
- IT Administration: MDT, PXE, PDQ Deploy & Inventory, Active Directory.
- Scripting Languages: Batch, PowerShell, Ruby, JSON, YAML.
- Browsers: Chrome, Safari, Firefox, MS Edge, IE.
- Hardware: Desktops, Laptops, MacBooks, Servers, NEC PBX, Switches, RPi3, iPhone, Android.
- Networking: LAN, VPN, TCP/IP, DNS, SSH, RDP, Firewalls (pfSense, PA-200), Nagios.
- Platforms: Windows 7 & 10, Mac, Linux Server, Windows Server 2012 R2, ESXi, ProxMox, Virtual Machines, Containers, AWS.

Experience

AEI Consultants at Walnut Creek. CA

Desktop Support Engineer (2017 – 2017)

- Maintained all responsibilities from my prior roles as a Desktop Support Analyst and IT Coordinator. This includes working helpdesk tickets, all aspects of Office 365 administration, and acting as a point of escalation for junior level helpdesk employees.
- Responsible for the overall performance of the Helpdesk and reported directly to the IT Director.
- Assisted IT Director whenever available to do so. Some examples below.
 - Taking point in the hiring process for new Helpdesk employees (interviewing, onboarding and training) as well as supervising, creating the training material and improving procedures as needed.
 - o Taking over stalled projects and getting them back on track.
- Assisted VP of Business Analytics and VP of Sales by representing the internal IT engineering aspect of companywide projects and build outs. Example: Google Sites to Office 365 SharePoint migration and SalesForce to Dynamic CRM migration.
- Responsible for assisting other departments and business units in coming up with, supporting and building out solutions to meet their needs.

Desktop Support Analyst (2016 – 2017)

- Maintained all responsibilities from my prior role as an IT Coordinator. This includes working helpdesk tickets and acting as a point of escalation for junior level helpdesk employees.
- Responsible for configuration and policy management for internal IT and its processes.
- Lead Office 365 administrator. Responsible for the following:
 - Onboarding User creation through AD, DirSync verification along with license and DL/group management.
 - Termination Quickly disabling accounts, shared inbox conversion and coordination with management in determining responsibility for that inbox.
 - Solving Office 365 related tickets.
 - Running mail traces to troubleshoot issues like spoofing.
 - · Managing domain white listing and black listing.
 - Managing DKIM, SPF and MX configuration through cPanel.
 - Managing application integration for apps like MailChimp and Zendesk.
 - Creating how-to documentation for both internal IT and end users.
 - The health of how Office 365 integrates into the local Active Directory.
 - Performing and coordinating eDiscovery efforts when necessary.
- Reduced technical debt and Helpdesk tickets by building and implementing three major systems into productions that massively streamlined our procedures.
 - A network monitoring system (Nagios Check_MK) to help alert us so we can quickly identify and preemptively troubleshoot remote circuits.
 - A zero-touch and light-touch imaging solution (MDT w/ PXE boot) for automated laptop/desktop deployment via a network connection.
 - A fully automated application deployment system (PDQ Deploy & Inventory) that includes applications updates, Windows patching, inventory and asset reporting.
- Leveraged PowerShell and batch scripting to add features and custom tools for our team to use in order to better support our users. Examples can be found on my GitHub.
- Emphasis on documentation and backups. My team is always able to quickly troubleshoot, reinstate or rebuild anything based off my documentation alone.
- Setup and moderated internal collaboration websites like our Wiki and KanBan board to keep us all on the same page.

IT Coordinator (2015 – 2016)

- Solved end user issues by responding to trouble tickets, taking calls, troubleshooting.
 over the phone and via remote desktop.
- Google Apps and Active Directory user accounts and PBX administration.
- Supported Android and iPhones.
- Desktop and laptop imaging and deployment.
- NEC PBX phone extension administration and configuration.

Bank of the West at San Ramon, CA

*IT Support Specialist 1 (*2013 – 2015)

- Supported all Bank of the West locations by taking calls, perform troubleshooting over the phone and via remote desktop and handle password resets for a dozen or so applications as well as verifying access rights. Supporting desktop configurations for proprietary software on the back end, mobile devices management and troubleshooting VPN issues. Remotely configuring server's to troubleshooting desktop software and hardware issues.
- Worked as Level 2 on weekends. Level 2 duties include taking ownership of global or critical issues and following ELA (escalation level agreement) procedures. Including reaching out to the appropriate on-call application technicians and becoming an acting liaison between management, application technicians and the end user base until the issue had been resolved. Also includes tickets too difficult for Level 1.
- Worked as ATM support on weekends. Taking calls from branches, troubleshooting issues and dispatching ATM technicians onsite to further troubleshoot or make repairs.
- I trained new Level 1 employees for the last six months of this position.

Education

DevOps Engineer and Full Stack Web Developer Training (4/14/2017 – present)

- Completed The Odin Project to learn full stack web development using Ruby on Rails.
- Completed the AWS Certified Developer Course from A Cloud Guru.
- Thorough understanding of GitHub and the basics of front end (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ReactJS) and back end (Ruby and Ruby on Rails, Serverless Framework for AWS) web development.
- Built the portfolio.ekpost.net web app to serve as my recent portfolio platform. It's a serverless website hosted on AWS, uses ReactJS as its front end and relies heavily on CodePipeline for deployment. Utilizes the following AWS services; IAM, Route53, S3, CloudFront, CodeBuild, CodePipeline and Lambda.
- Built the eric-post.ddns.net web app which served as my previous blog/portfolio platform.
 Built several Ansible playbooks including one that provisions the Ruby environment for my blog app. I then use Capistrano to deploy the app itself to the web server.
- Understanding of DevOps philosophies like The Twelve Factors, AGILE, SCRUM, Test driven development and Infrastructure as code.

PowerShell Training (2015)

Completed the Microsoft Virtual Academy track for PowerShell.